# JOHANNES **LEANDER**

Frontend/UI Engineer



Ambitious frontend engineer who enjoys the challenge of creating advanced applications with the end user in mind.

Possesses practical knowledge in UI/UX and believes that the user experience is as important as the technical solutions.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# Frontend UI/UX Developer

Capish International

Responsible for the UI/UX of a web based analytics and visualization application. *Required skills:* React, HTML5, Javascript, CSS3, Agile Development

# 2010 - 2012 UI Developer

Present

Percepium

Lund

Malmö

Created the graphical user interface for a Learning Management System. Required skills: C#/.NET, Silverlight, SQL Server, Design Patterns, Interaction Design

# 2008 - 2010 IT Consultant

Sogeti

Linköping

Consultant developer with focus on UI and GIS development *Required skills:* C#/.NET, C++, Web Forms, GIS Development, ArcGIS

#### **CONTACT ME**

johannesleander@outlook.com

+46761984022

in linkedin.com/in/johleander

www.johannesleander.com

Soldat Friares gata 28 22651 Lund

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Trainee Program, High Tech Consulting**

Sogeti

Linköping

Theoretical courses mixed with practical experience for customer (SAAB Aeronautics).

Certifications & Courses: Using C++ in Embedded System

Real Time for UML 2.1,

Develop Linux Based Embedded Systems

ISTQB/ISEB Software Testing Foundation Certificate

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

Javascript

C#/.NET

Data Visualization

User Experience

User Experience
Interaction Design
Project Management

• • • • •

2003 - 2008

 $\square$ 

2008

### M.Sc, Media Technology

Linköping University

Norrköping

Master of Science degree in Media Technology from Linköping University.

The purpose of the education was to teach how to combine technical engineering topics with more creative ones.

# 7

# LANGUAGES

Swedish
English
German